# **Cindy Chang**

# Front-End/UX Developer

#### **About Me**

I am a 37-year-old Front-End / UX Developer, originally from California but now residing in the Netherlands. I love the intersection between design and development and started as a graphic designer and now work as a Front-End and UX developer.

# **Experience**

## Senior UX Engineer (Backbase)

2022 - present

 Part of the Design System team, leading best practices and governance within different disciplines, ensuring alignment with design and development in code and Figma.

## Front-End / UX Developer (Creative Fabrica)

2019-2021 - Netherlands

- Front-End development for migrating existing Wordpress site to React and creating new projects in React, NextJS and Typescript.
- Maintaining, building and improving main corporate site's front end and building new UX elements in JavaScript, HTML5 and SASS.
- Worked closely with stakeholders, designers and backend developers to build and modify existing features on the site.

#### Front-End Designer (Freelance)

2018-2019 - New Orleans

- Front-end design, UI/UX for various clients. Working with sites built
  with various static site generators such as Hugo and Jekyll and
  CMS platforms such as Craft and Wordpress.
- Worked directly with stakeholders: wireframing, prototyping, design, build-out, developer collaboration and troubleshooting.

#### **Design & Web Development** (Domino Data Lab)

2016-2018 - New Orleans

- Lead Creative for the Marketing team, working closely with major stakeholders to create web and graphic solutions for a scaling startup.
- Designed, developed and maintained main corporate website, blog and event websites run on Jekyll and Wordpress.



hello@cindychang.co

31 0638091532

cindychang.co

cindychangy

## **Education**

San Francisco State University
Marketing Communications, 2002

# Design

Figma Sketch Adobe Creative Suite Invision

#### Dev

React

NextJS

JavaScript

Typescript

Jest

HTML5

CSS3

SASS

PHP (Wordpress)

GIT

#### **Hobbies**

I love to travel, blog about true crime, bake, do crossfit and watch ice hockey (Go Red Wings).